Hi.
大家好
I'm with Jen who's a lead designer with Google Apps Accessibility.
现在我们有请 Jen Googles 应用无障碍的首席设计师
And Jen has over 15 years of design experience.
Jen 在设计行业有 15 年多的设计经验
And today, Jen, I'm really curious to get your insight.
Jen 我今天非常想听听你的想法
Our students have learned about user interaction and information design.
我们的学员在学习用户互动和信息设计
What else is important when it comes to designing a good product?
要设计一个好产品 还有哪些比较重点的点需要考虑？
I think one of the key things that a lot of people overlook initially, but
我觉得很关键的一点 很多人一开始忽略了
is extremely important is accessibility.
但其实非常重要的一点 就是无障碍功能
>> Mm-hm.
恩
And what's accessibility?
什么是无障碍？
>> Accessibility is about trying to make products that are accessible and
无障碍就是说让所有人 包括残疾人
usable by all people regardless if they have a disability or
都可以使用产品
not It's closely related to universal design, which is all about the process
这和通用化设计有紧密的关系
of making products usable by people with all ranges of abilities,
通用化设计是指让所有能力水平的人都能使用产品
as well as they can use them in all ranges of situations.
并且能在任何情况下使用
So just thinking about if you can envision a user using
想一想你是否能想象用户
your product with one hand, maybe it wasn't designed intentionally for
用一只手使用你的产品 就算不是故意这样设计的
that, but can they use it with one hand?
但是他们是否能够一只手使用产品？
And this would benefit users that might have certain motor impairments, but
这对一些有特定运动缺陷的用户很有用
it would also benefit users that maybe have a hand busy holding a baby or
但是 同样地 有时候用户需要用一只手抱着婴儿
a large bag of groceries.
或者提着一大袋东西 这也很有用
That's kind of the idea behind accessibility design.
这就是无障碍设计的理念
>> Okay, and you mention some of the impairments that someone might have.
好的 你有提到一些人可能有的一些缺陷
What other sorts of impairments might people bring to a product that
还有哪些其他的缺陷
might prevent them from successfully using a product in the first place?
会妨碍用户成功使用产品呢？
>> There's a number of common impairments that we consider, and
我们考虑的有很多常见的缺陷
they range from having visual impairments, being color blind,
比如视力缺陷 色盲
having hearing impairments, cognitive impairments, and motor impairments.
听力缺陷、认知缺陷、运动缺陷等
And the thing to note with all of these is that
还需要注意的是
there's a wide range of severity within each of these impairments, so
每种缺陷都有不同的严重程度
you could have just slight vision loss to being totally blind.
比如有的人只是轻微的视力下降 而有的人是完全失明
And the other thing is that a lot of people
另外还有 有不少人
tend to have multiple impairments at one time.
可能同一时间患有多种缺陷
It definitely makes things interesting to design for, but
这对设计来说是有趣的挑战
it's certainly a reality that we need to consider.
同时 这也是现实中需要考虑的内容
And one of the things that I always love to talk to people about and remind them,
另外 我经常讨论并提醒别人
when you start to think about designing for people with disabilities a lot of
当你开始思考为残疾人进行设计的时候
people tend to kind of treat them as like they're in a separate group.
很多人会把他们看作是完全独立的群体
And it's a group of people that you could consider or could not consider.
是一群你可以考虑也可以不考虑的人
>> Mm. >> But in reality, we're all going to
— 恩 — 但现实中
have some sort of impairment most likely and within our lifetime.
我们整个人生里 总会遭遇某些缺陷
One of the important things that I feel that people need to keep in mind is that
我觉得大家应该谨记的重要的一点就是
when you're thinking about people with disabilities a lot of designers and
当你在想到残疾人的时候 很多设计师
different people tend to think of them as a totally separate group that may or
和其他人会把他们想成完全独立的群体
may not, or can or can not be considered in the process.
在过程中可能会可能不会 可以也可以不考虑的一群人
But in actuality,
但是实际上
all of us are going to have a disability at some point in our lives.
在生活中的某个时间段 我们也会遭遇缺陷
And these things can be temporary, like a broken arm.
可能会是暂时的 比如手臂骨折
They can be situational,
也可能是某些特殊情况
like if you're riding a bike and maybe can't see your small phone screen.
比如正在骑自行车 不能看小小的手机屏幕
And they can be just natural progression of aging.
也可以是自然的衰老过程
So it's really important to consider these things.
所以我们需要考虑这些东西
because if you're not, in a sense you're not considering
如果不考虑 那也就是说你没有为某个时间点的自己
how to design these products for yourself at some point.
设计产品
>> Yeah.
是的
So, what other considerations, I guess, or why would it be important for
那其他还需要考虑什么呢？或者说 为什么企业家
entrepreneurs to think about accessibility first?
需要考虑到无障碍功能呢？
>> Well, one huge thing is that there is a large population of people
首先 重要的一点是 有很多的人
with disabilities.
是带有残疾的
There's a lot of great research out there about the demographics of people
外面有很多对人口特征的调查研究
and we compiled some research and noted that there are more people with
我们也进行了一些研究 发现
color blindness than there are native English speakers in the world.
有色盲的人甚至比世界上以英语为母语的人还要多
>> Oh wow. >> So this is a huge population.
— 哇 — 这是很庞大的一个群体
>> Yeah.
是的
And just thinking as an entrepreneur, that's a huge pool of people, and
作为一个企业家 从利润的角度出发
an audience that you can tap into from a financial profit standpoint.
你有一个可以开发的广大的人群
Obviously, another motivator if you're looking to get involved
另外 如果你在教育或政府部门
in education or government.
寻求投资
>> Mm-hm. >> There's some legal considerations
— 恩 — 那就有一些法律问题要考虑
there and some legal standards that you need to meet.
需要满足一些法律标准
But I think most importantly, what we have found is that, when you consider
但我认为最重要的是 我们发现
accessibility up front, it often leads to a much better product for everybody.
当你考虑无障碍功能时 通常会得到所有人都觉得更好的产品
>> Yeah.
是的
And what's one example of a product like that that you've seen?
那你能举一个你知道的这样的例子么？
>> Well, one really simple simple example and
恩 一个非常非常简单的
a straightforward thing that everyone can start doing if you're designing
直接的例子就是在设计数码产品时
a digital product, is think about can a user
你要考虑用户是否能只使用键盘
complete all the necessary tasks on your product using just a keyboard.
完成所有必要的任务
So, not only is this beneficial to somebody that uses a screen reader or
这不仅仅对适用屏幕阅读器的用户
doesn't have the dexterity to use a mouse, but it's also really powerful,
或者是不能够使用鼠标的用户有用
or useful, for the power users that you might have.
同时还对你的高级用户很有帮助
>> Yeah. >> That like to use keyboards,
— 是的 — 他们喜欢用键盘
because they feel it's more efficient.
觉得这样更有效率
>> Mm.
恩
Cool.
太棒了